让我们来谈谈
Let's talk about
CSS 的另一个极其重要的方面，
another extremely important aspect of CSS,
这是定位模式。
which are positioning modes.
而这个是更复杂的讲座之一
And this one is one of the more complex lectures
本节的
of this section
所以一定要好好注意。
and so make sure to pay good attention.
所以在 CSS 中，
So in CSS,
有几种不同的定位模式。
there are a couple of different positioning modes.
但更重要的
But the more important ones
以及我们现在要讨论的那些
and the ones we are going to talk about for now
是正常流量和绝对定位。
are the normal flow and absolute positioning.
所以从正常流程开始，
So starting with normal flow,
它只是元素的默认定位
it is simply the default positioning of elements
在我们的页面上。
on our page.
或者我们也可以实现正常流
Or we can also achieve the normal flow
通过将位置设置为相对值。
by setting position to the value of relative.
所以在这种情况下，我们说一个元素是“流动的”，
So in this case, we say that an element is 'in flow',
这基本上意味着元素的布局
which basically means that the elements are laid out
根据HTML中的源代码。
according to the source code in the HTML.
所以这很简单。
So this is very straightforward.
这只是我们一直看到的行为
It is simply the behavior that we have been seeing
直到这一点。
up until this point.
所以请记住，这被称​​为正常流程。
So just keep in mind that that is called normal flow.
另一方面，现在我们有绝对定位，
Now on the other hand, we have absolute positioning,
这基本上允许我们绝对定位元素
which basically allows us to absolutely position elements
页面上的任何位置。
anywhere on the page.
现在我们可以实现这种定位模式，
Now we can achieve this positioning mode,
所以我们可以绝对定位一个元素
so we can position an element absolutely
通过设置它的位置属性
by setting it's position property
到绝对值。
to the value of absolute.
所以在这种情况下，
And so in this case,
然后从正常流程中删除该元素
the element is then removed from the normal flow
我们说它“没有流量”。
and we say that it is 'out of flow'.
现在这个元素会发生什么
Now what happens with this element is
它完全失去了对周围元素的任何影响。
that it completely loses any impact on surrounding elements.
事实上，它甚至可能与它们重叠。
And in fact, it might even overlap them.
所以这是经常发生的事情
So that's something common that happens
具有绝对定位的元素。
with absolutely positioned elements.
现在，为了实际定位元素
Now, in order to actually position the element
绝对定位，
that is absolutely positioned,
我们可以使用顶部、底部、左侧或右侧属性
we can use the top, bottom, left or right properties
为了定位该元素。
in order to position that element.
并且这种定位将发生在相关的
And that positioning is going to happen in relation
到一个相对定位的容器。
to a relatively positioned container.
现在，我知道这听起来有点令人困惑
Now, I know that this sounds kind of confusing
所以让我们实际看看这种情况在实践中发生。
and so let's actually see this happening in practice.
所以我们在这个讲座中要做的是
So what we're going to do in this lecture is
创建一个位于外部的 Like 按钮
to create a Like button that is located outside
我们居中的容器。
of our centered container.
所以让我在演示中展示这一点。
So let me show that in the demo.
所以在最后，我们有这个 Like 按钮。
And so here at the very end, we have this Like button.
例如，当我们展开页面时，
And as we expand the page for example,
你看到这个元素总是保持不变
you see that this element always stays
在完全相同的位置，对吧？
on exactly the same position, right?
所以它不受任何周围元素的影响
So it's not impacted by any of the surrounding elements
这更加明显
and that is even better visible
如果我们进一步减少页面。
if we decrease the page even further.
所以在这里我们甚至有元素的情况
So here we even have that situation where the element
实际上在这里重叠了这个相关的帖子元素。
actually overlaps this related posts element right here.
对？
Right?
所以你会看到这个元素没有影响
And so you'll see that this element is not impacting
它也没有受到影响
and it's also not being impacted
通过任何周围的元素。
by any of the surrounding elements.
它总是只是简单地呆在这个地方，
It always just simply stays here in this place,
无论页面的其余部分发生什么。
no matter what happens to the rest of the page.
这是一个很好的例子
And so this is a great example
一个绝对定位的元素。
of an absolutely positioned element.
现在我们应该在哪里行动lly 加价
Now where should we actually put the mark-up
这个按钮？
for this button?
所以HTML...
So the HTML...
好吧，至少现在这并不重要。
Well, it doesn't really matter at least for now.
所以让我们把它放在正文的末尾。
So let's just actually put it here at the end of the body.
所以在任何其他元素之后。
So after any other element.
所以实际上即使在容器之后。
So actually even after the container.
但同样，目前这还不是最重要的部分
But again, for now that's not the most important part
我们稍后会改变它。
and we will change this a little bit later.
所以让我们使用按钮元素
So let's use the button element
我们也已经在我们的编码挑战中使用了它。
that we have also used in our coding challenges already.
然后在这里我只写'Like'，
And then here I'm just going to write 'Like',
然后让我们在这里添加一个漂亮的表情符号，
and then let's just add a nice emoji here,
在 Windows 中你可以做什么
which in Windows you can do
通过同时击中控制命令和空间。
by hitting control command and space at the same time.
在 Windows 上，您可以打开表情符号选择器
And on Windows, you can open up the emoji picker
通过点击 Windows 键加点。
by hitting the Windows key plus the dot.
所以这不是任何 VS 代码扩展。
So this is not any VS code extension.
这只是提供的功能
This is simply functionality that is provided
由操作系统。
by the operating system.
再说一遍，控制 Mac 上的命令空间
So again, control command space on the Mac
和 Windows 加上 Windows 10 上的点。
and Windows plus the dot on Windows 10.
所以让我们在这里寻找心
So let's just search for hearts here
和...是的。
and... yeah.
VS 代码类型的转换
VS code kind of transforms this
出于某种原因进入这个灰色符号。
into this gray symbol here for some reason.
但别管那个了。
But nevermind about that.
所以我们就来这里吧
So let's just come here
我们的按钮现在应该在这里的某个地方。
and our button should be somewhere here now.
所以现在，它就在这里。
And so right now, it is simply here.
所以在所有其他元素之后，
So simply after all the other elements,
因为现在，当然，它仍然处于正常流程中。
because for now, of course, it is in the normal flow still.
所以我们还没有声明绝对位置。
So we haven't declared position absolute on it yet.
因此，它只是在流动中
And so therefore it is simply in the flow
它的位置很简单
and it's simply positioned right
毕竟其他元素。
after all the other elements.
但现在让我们真正改变它。
But now let's actually change that.
因此，让我们使用按钮选择层。
So let's select the tier using button.
让我们先给它一些视觉风格。
Let's first give it some visual styles.
还添加一些填充。
Adding some padding as well.
我们也可以使用这个技巧
And we can also use that trick
定义游标属性，
of defining the cursor property,
正如我在挑战赛中向你展示的那样，
as I also show it to you in the challenge,
并将其设置为指针，以便我们真正得到那只手。
and set it to pointer so that we actually get that hand.
对？
Right?
所以现在它看起来更好一点。
So now it looks a little bit nicer.
你会看到还有这个悬停状态，
And you'll see there's also this hover state,
我们当然可以定制，
which we could of course customize,
但我们不要花时间在这上面。
but let's not spend time on that.
但是我们现在将立即设置位置
But instead we will now immediately set the position
就像我在上一张幻灯片中向您展示的那样绝对。
to absolute just like I showed you in the previous slide.
所以让我们保存一下，看看它是什么样子的。
So let's give it a save and see what it looks like.
但就目前而言，它看起来仍然非常相似。
But for now it still looks pretty similar.
那是因为我们还没有真正定位它
And that's because we didn't really position it yet
使用我还提到的四个属性之一，
using one of the four properties that I also mentioned,
所以顶部，左侧，右侧和底部。
so top, left, right and bottom.
所以现在让我们实际使用顶部
And so let's for now actually go with top
并在此处将其设置为零，
and set it to zero here,
这始终是一个很好的起点。
which is always a good starting point.
让我们说左边，零也是。
And let's say left, zero as well.
给它一个保存。
Give it a save.
而现在它可能已经消失了。
And now it might be gone.
是啊，就是。
Yeah, it is.
那是因为现在它就在这里。
And so that's because now it is right here.
所以我们将它的顶部位置设置为零
So we set its top position to zero
所以现在它在页面的最顶部
and so now it's at the very top of the page
因为这里的这些像素，
because these pixels here,
所以零像素，至少现在，
so the zero pixels, at least for now,
从视口的顶部开始计算，
are being counted from the top of the viewport,
所以这里页面的这个可见部分。
so of this visible part of the page here.
因此，如果我们将其更改为底部，例如，
So if we change this to bottom, for example,
那么它应该在视口的底部。
then it should be here at the bottom of the viewport.
所以默认情况下，这个元素是定位的
So by default, this element is positioned
关于视口，
in relation to the viewport,
这又是页面的可见部分。
which again is this visible part of the page.
好的。
Okay.
所以现在它留在这里，
So now it stays here,
这是一个非常奇怪的地方。
which is a very weird place for it to be.
但这里需要注意的重要一点是，事实上，
But what is important to note here is that in fact,
此元素已完全从流程中取出
this element has been completely taken out of the flow
它现在甚至悬停在此内容上。
and it's now even hovering over this content.
所以就好像其余的内容都不存在
So it is as if the rest of the content is not even there
这变得更加明显
and that is becoming even more apparent
例如，当我们改变窗口的大小时。
as we change, for example, the size of the window.
让我们回到原来的位置。
And let's go back to where we were.
把它放回顶部。
Put it back to top.
当然，我们也可以将它移动到其他位置。
And of course we can also move it to some other position.
所以它不必完全粘合
So it doesn't have to be exactly glued
到顶部和左侧。
to the top and the left.
但是我们可以，例如，将它向下移动 50 个像素
But we can, for example, move it 50 pixels down
向右多 50 像素，
and 50 pixels more to the right,
从左边数到这里。
counting here from the left side.
好的。
Okay.
所以这是非常非常基本的
So that's the very, very fundamentals
的绝对定位。
of absolute positioning.
但非常重要的是要了解
But what is very important to understand is
这里的这 50 个像素需要
that these 50 pixels here need to be
关于某事。
in relation to something.
所以，正如我刚才提到的，
And so, as I just mentioned a minute ago,
默认情况下，这 50 个像素是相关的
by default, these 50 pixels here are in relation
到视口，
to the viewport,
所以页面的可见部分在浏览器中。
so the visible part of the page here in the browser.
这就是元素向下移动的原因
That's the reason why the element moved down here
当我将底部设置为零时到这个角落。
to this corner when I set the bottom to zero.
然而，这通常不是我们想要的。
However, that is usually not what we want.
所以通常，我们想要绝对定位元素
So usually, we want to absolutely position the element
相对于其他一些父元素。
in relation to some other parent element.
为了做到这一点，
And in order to do that,
我们需要专门设置位置
we need to specifically set the position
该父元素的相对关系。
of that parent element to relative.
好的。
Okay.
所以在这种情况下，
So in this case,
我们希望这个元素在这里被定位
we want this element here to be positioned
在页面的右下角。
in the right bottom corner of the page.
所以页面而不是视口。
So of the page and not of the viewport.
所以让我们试试吧。
So let's try that.
所以我们说...
So let's say...
底部 50 像素，
bottom 50 pixels,
实际上让我们把它留在这里
and actually let's keep this here
然后复制它
and just copy it
然后我会把它注释掉
and then I will comment it out
把它放在这里作为参考。
to keep it here as a reference.
但我们想要的是距底部 50 像素
But what we want is 50 pixels from the bottom
和右侧 50 像素。
and 50 pixels from the right.
因此，它再次将其移动到视口中的这个位置，
So again, it moves it to this place in the viewport,
但我们想把它放在这里，
but we want it down here,
所以从页面，对吧？
so from the page, right?
所以我们需要将位置设置为相对
And so we need to set position to relative
基本上在页面上。
on the page basically.
这就是身体元素。
And so that is the body element.
所以让我们这样做。
So let's do that.
让我们去身体，
Let's go to body,
就在这里。
which is right here.
让我们将它的位置设置为...
and let's set it's position to...
相对的。
Relative.
给它一个保存。
Give it a save.
现在，当我们下到这里时，
And now as we go down here,
然后就在这里。
then here it is.
伟大的。
Great.
让我们稍微调整一下页面大小
And let's resize the page a little bit
现在无论发生什么，
and now no matter what happens,
元素始终正确定位d
the element is always correctly positioned
在身体的右下角。
in the bottom right corner of the body.
伟大的。
Great.
所以我希望这是有道理的。
So I hope that made sense.
当然，它不必总是在身体上。
And of course, it doesn't have to be at the body always.
所以我们也可以把它放在里面
So we could also position this inside
任何其他父元素，
of any other parent element,
这不是身体。
which is not the body.
所以让我们举个例子，在这里尝试容器。
So let's for example, try here to container.
但为了做到这一点，
But in order to do that,
该元素实际上需要在容器内
the element actually needs to be inside of the container
因为否则这不是父元素
because otherwise this is not a parent element
按钮，对吧？
of the button, right?
所以让我们把它带出这里
So let's take this out of here
并将其放在其他地方。
and put it somewhere else.
而且在哪里并不重要。
And it doesn't really matter where.
重要的是它需要在某个地方
All that matters is that it needs to be somewhere
在这个容器内，
inside of this container,
所以这个带有容器类的 div 元素就可以了。
so this div element with the container class on it.
我认为....实际上是这个地方
And I think....actually the place
在语义上最有意义的地方
where it's semantically makes the most sense
在标题中。
is here in the header.
所以文章的标题，
So the header of the article,
所以这里的这个地方其实是司空见惯的
so this place here is actually a commonplace
您认为“赞”按钮有意义的地方
where you would think a Like button makes sense
在这样的博客文章中，对吧？
in a blog post like this, right?
所以让我们把它放在那里，
And so let's put it there,
即使在视觉上它不会出现在那里
even though visually it's not going to appear there
因为再次，我们绝对定位这个元素。
because again, we are positioning this element absolutely.
所以如果我们给它一个保存，
So if we give it a save,
那么现在什么都不会改变。
then for now nothing will have changed.
它仍然在这里。
It is still right here.
但是现在让我们尝试添加相对位置
But now let's try to add position relative
到这里的这个容器。
to this container here.
所以...
So...
相对位置。
Position relative.
某处有一个错字。
And there was a typo somewhere.
所以现在它应该在别的地方。
And so now it should be somewhere else.
现在它看起来好像在同一个地方，
And for now it does look as if it's in the same place,
但如果我们现在改变这个，
but if we change this now,
然后你会看到它现在在右上角
then you'll see that it is here in the top right corner now
的容器元素。
of the container element.
因此，为了可视化这一点，让我们检查容器。
So to visualize this, let's inspect the container.
所以在这里，蓝色部分是内容。
And so here, the blue part is the content.
所以你看到 Like 按钮现在是 50 像素
And so there you see that the Like button is now 50 pixels
从容器的底部和右侧。
from the bottom and from the right of the container.
再说一遍
And again that is
因为容器现在是第一个父元素
because the container is now the first parent element
位置设置为相对。
that has position set to relative.
好的。
All right.
为了使这一点更加清晰，
00:12:39,130​​ --> 00:12:43,023
让我们看一下对此的图形解释。
And to make this even more crystal clear,
let's take a look at a graphical explanation of this.
所以让我们想象一下我们有这种
So let's imagine that we have this kind
黄色元素在这里与容器类
of yellow element here with the container class
并且它的位置设置为相对。
and it has its position set to relative.
然后我们有另一个元素，就是这里的这个，
Then we have another element which is this one here,
所以这个橙色元素
so this orange element
并且它的位置设置为绝对。
and it has its position set to absolute.
它的顶部也设置为 100 像素
And it also has the top set to 100 pixels
左侧设置为 200 像素。
and the left set to 200 pixels.
因此，它将恰好位于 100 像素
And so therefore, it will be located exactly 100 pixels
从其相对定位的容器元素的顶部
from the top of it's relatively positioned container element
距离它的左侧 200 像素，
and 200 pixels from the left of it,
再次，第一个相对定位的容器元素。
again, first relatively positioned container element.
值得一提的是
And it's important to mention
它是第一个父元素
that it is the first parent element
位置设置为相对
that has position set to relative
将从中放置绝对定位的元素。
from which the absolutely positioned element will be placed.
好的。
Okay.
所以我希望有了这个可视化，
And so I hope that with this visualization,
它变得更加明显
it became even more obvious
绝对定位在 CSS 中的工作原理。
how absolute positioning works in CSS.
让我们实际上只是尝试另一个元素
And let's actually just try another element
作为第一个相对定位的容器。
as the first relatively positioned container.
所以让我们在标题上这样做。
So let's do that on the header.
所以这里的这个按钮在这个标题里面。
So this button here is inside of this header.
所以我们可以使用这个标题
And so we could use this header
作为我们想要的父元素
as the parent element inside of which we want
绝对定位此按钮。
to absolutely position this button.
因此，让我们转到帖子标题。
So let's go to a post header.
把它放在这里。
Place that here.
现在...
And now...
开始了。
Here we go.
所以现在就在这里。
So now here it is.
再次使用开发工具
Once again using the dev tools
所以我们可以检查整个元素。
so we can check out this entire element.
事实上，按钮现在看起来是 50 像素
And in fact, it looks like the button is now 50 pixels
从底部和从右侧
from the bottom and from the right
它是新的相对定位的容器。
of it's new relatively positioned container.
好的。
Okay.
所以让我们实际删除这个。
So let's actually remove this one.
所以把它和这个评论出来，
So commenting it out and this one as well,
因为我们真正想要的是我们一开始所做的。
because what we really want is what we did in the beginning.
所以我们希望它相对于身体定位。
So we want it to be positioned in relation to the body.
好的。
All right.
所以我希望这是有道理的。
So I hope this made sense.
因此，作为本次讲座的绝对定位回顾，
And so as a recap of this lecture with absolute positioning,
你基本上可以放任何你想要的元素
you can basically put any element that you want
您希望它出现在页面上的任何位置，
wherever you want it to be on the page,
这当然很有帮助。
which of course can be quite helpful.
现在重要的是
Now what's important is
你不要滥用这种新发现的力量。
that you don't abuse this newfound power.
因此，例如，不要使用它来构建复杂的布局。
So don't use this to build complex layouts, for example.
相反，我们对单个元素使用绝对定位
Instead, we use absolute positioning for single elements
喜欢这个按钮或其他小东西，
like this button or other small things,
就像我将在下一个视频中向您展示一样。
just like I will show you in the next video.
但在现实世界中，我们不使用这个例子，
But in the real world, we don't use this for example,
将此菜单放置在此处，
to position this menu here,
喜欢这里在页面的顶部
like here on the top of the page
或在此处放置例如此作者图片
or to position for example this author image here
页面上的任何位置。
anywhere on the page.
对于那些东西，我们实际上会使用特殊的技术
For those things, we will actually use special techniques
用于建筑布局。
for building layouts.
所以请记住，我们总是不简单地达到
So just keep in mind that we always don't simply reach
对于绝对定位，
for absolute positioning,
例如构建布局。
for example to build layouts.
但这一切都会随着练习而来
But all of this will come with practice
所以暂时不要太担心。
and so don't worry too much about it for now.